<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on cbrtl</title>
    <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on cbrtl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vyse</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/vyse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/vyse/</guid>
      <description>Vyse VyseAn elegant and embeddable programming languageVisit the language spec »Website »Report Bug•Request FeatureCI Status [MIT License](https://github.com/tterb/atomic-design-ui/blob/master/LICENSEs)
Vyse is a dynamically typed, interpreted and fast scriptling language inspired by Lua for rapid prototyping of applications like video games. Programmers familiar with Lua/Javascript can pick up the language within an hour. Vyse also comes with a C++ API for frictionless embedding in projects.
Table of Contents Vyse Table of Contents Goal Overview Roadmap Implementation Lexing / Tokenizing (Source string -&amp;gt; Token) Compiling (Tokens -&amp;gt; Bytecode) VyVM Building Benchmarks Tests Editor-Support Development Goal Vyse aims to pick up after the Lua programming language, by adding popularly desired features on top of it, whilst providing similar speed and minimalism as Lua.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Ratenect</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/ratenect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/ratenect/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This project is being maintained by Ankur Khandelwal
India has over 3.2 million registered NGOs (Non-Governmental Organisations) across its territory. The voluntary sector has always played an important role in supporting the government as a partner in nation-building and is heavily funded by the government as well as by private institutions. In 2018 only, companies contributed US$1 Billion to CSR initiatives, according to a survey.
Considering the vast impact and significance of the sector, it becomes very important to tackle the challenges present here as well as to improve and increase its accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/faq/</guid>
      <description>Why the weird name? It comes from the C stdlib function cbrtl.
But why does the C standard library have these weird names?
Well there is a little bit of trivia to it, in older versions of ANSI C, only the first 6 characters of an identifier were considered in the compiler. So most standard library functions in C have odd names like strstr, strtod, alloca and so on&amp;hellip;
Oh, and also because every other GitHub organization name was taken&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcasing your project on cbrtl</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/project-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/project-showcase/</guid>
      <description>Helloo again.
This post intends to establish some minor ordinances surrounding project ideas and showcases. cbrtl was created with the intent of promoting the spirit of Open Source. Often times, some of the most interesting Open Source projects live in lesser known corners of GitHub, gathering dust on a lonesome profile with 3-5 followers and an occasionally active commit graph.
With cbrtl, we can shine some light on these pieces of software, benefitting both the creator/maintainer and the people who can use these projects as reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with cbrtl and FOSS</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>So you read up on open source, read up on cbrtl and want to start hacking. There are some preliminaries that you should take care of first. I will list them in order:
Create a GitHub account. Set up git on your local computer. If you&amp;rsquo;re on windows, download GitBash and follow the install instructions. Get a personal test repo set up and try out commands like push, commit, pull etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/what-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/what-and-why/</guid>
      <description>What is cbrtl? cbrtl is an attempt at creating a tight knit group of programmers who like making fun stuff and being involved in Open Source development. We are based out of Silicon Institute of Technology, Odisha.
What do we do here? A lot of stuff, actually!
Create fun and unique projects. Either in groups or in isolation. Organize community and online showcases for group and individual projects. Contribute to Open Source projects both in cbrtl and in other communities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
