<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>faq on cbrtl</title>
    <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/tags/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in faq on cbrtl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cbrtl.github.io/tags/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/faq/</guid>
      <description>Before you ask...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="why-the-weird-name">Why the weird name?</h3>
<p>It comes from the C stdlib function <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cpp/c-runtime-library/reference/cbrt-cbrtf-cbrtl?view=msvc-160">cbrtl</a>.</p>
<p>But why does the C standard library have these weird names?</p>
<p>Well there is a little bit of trivia to it, in older versions of ANSI C, only the first 6 characters of an
identifier were considered in the compiler.
So most standard library functions in C have odd names like <code>strstr</code>, <code>strtod</code>, <code>alloca</code> and so on&hellip;</p>
<p>Oh, and also because every other GitHub organization name was taken&hellip;</p>
<h3 id="why-conjure-a-community-out-of-nowhere">Why conjure a community out of nowhere?</h3>
<p>Some of my acquaintances from other colleges have clubs, groups and spaces dedicated to open source and software
development. Couple of days ago, I came across IIT Roorkee&rsquo;s <a href="https://sdslabs.co/">SDSLabs </a> and PES Uni&rsquo;s <a href="https://pesos.github.io/">PES Open Source</a>.  After looking into it
a bit more, turns out most colleges these days have their own groups for related stuff.</p>
<p>We thought it would be fun to have a similar group of like minded developers from our college.</p>
<p>Is it too ambitious? We won&rsquo;t know until we don&rsquo;t try.</p>
<h3 id="what-is-it-that-cbrtl-aims-to-do-exactly">What is it that cbrtl aims to do exactly?</h3>
<p>Good question. We don&rsquo;t have a concrete answer because the direction we end up going in will be decided by the fellow community members. That said, I&rsquo;ll throw in most of what we&rsquo;ve gathered from our goal so far, and you decide if you like the sound of it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Contributing to Open Source.</li>
<li>Forming teams for hackathons and CP events.</li>
<li>Collaborating on projects together.</li>
<li>Showcasing projects from individuals and teams.</li>
<li>Code reviews and educational blogs (ones that haven&rsquo;t been done to death before&hellip;).</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-platforms-are-you-present-on">What platforms are you present on?</h3>
<p>For now, our presence is limited to <a href="https://discord.gg/3qry3u569v">Discord</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/cbrtl">GitHub organization</a>.
Mostly because these are very solid platforms and we are tight on the number of people moderating.</p>
<h3 id="what-skills-do-i-need">What skills do I need?</h3>
<p>Not much.</p>
<ul>
<li>The ability to code.</li>
<li>The willingness to learn.</li>
<li>Basic knowledge of Git and GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<p>Even 1 and 3 are optional.</p>
<h3 id="where-do-i-join">Where do I join?</h3>
<p>As mentioned earlier,  you can join the <a href="https://discord.gg/3qry3u569v">Discord</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/cbrtl">GitHub organization</a>.
More info on <a href="/">Getting started with cbrtl and Open Source</a>.</p>
<h3 id="is-there-anything-i-can-do-to-help">Is there anything I can do to help?</h3>
<p>Yes. <del>PayTM me some cash</del>. <em>ahem</em>, you can volunteer to help us keep the community thriving. We are looking for volunteers who can help with:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Front end development</strong>: To touch up the current blog site.</li>
<li><strong>Moderation</strong>: To manage the discord server and the GitHub org.</li>
<li><strong>Code reviews</strong>: To mandate some code quality for those who demand it.</li>
<li><strong>Technical Writers</strong>: To aid in writing blog posts.</li>
<li><strong>Editors</strong>: A second pair of eyes helps catch common mistakes in writing :)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="is-this-an-official-college-club">Is this an official college club?</h3>
<p>Nope, not yet. This is an entirely independent student initiative that is looking for active participation.
This is a mostly decentralized group of like-minded programmers.</p>
<h3 id="will-there-be-exciting-cash-prizes">Will there be exciting cash prizes?</h3>
<p>No. I want to be upfront about it. Those of us who end up forming hackathon teams may earn some on their own,
but we want to keep this community closeted to people who code because they like making fun stuff. Of course,
that is not to say we discredit any other motivation you may have.</p>
<p>As such, we won&rsquo;t conduct any competitions with cash prizes for the foreseeable future.
Other clubs (which are official) in our college do a great job at that regardless.</p>
<h3 id="what-kinds-of-events-can-i-expect">What kinds of events can I expect?</h3>
<p>Other than project showcases and on-demand code review sessions, we are open to other ideas.</p>
<p>Not as much of an &rsquo;event&rsquo; but you can expect group projects that will (hopefully) be active throughout.</p>
<h3 id="i-have-some-other-questions-where-can-i-ask">I have some other questions, where can I ask?</h3>
<p>You&rsquo;re more than welcome on the mailing list, or in the discord server 😁</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
