<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>guidelines on cbrtl</title>
    <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/tags/guidelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guidelines on cbrtl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cbrtl.github.io/tags/guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Showcasing your project on cbrtl</title>
      <link>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/project-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cbrtl.github.io/posts/project-showcase/</guid>
      <description>Some things to keep in mind while adding your project</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Helloo again.</p>
<p>This post intends to establish some minor ordinances surrounding project ideas and showcases.
cbrtl was created with the intent of promoting the spirit of Open Source.
Often times, some of the most interesting Open Source projects live in lesser known corners of GitHub, gathering dust on a lonesome profile with 3-5 followers and an occasionally active commit graph.</p>
<p>With cbrtl, we can shine some light on these pieces of software, benefitting both the
creator/maintainer and the people who can use these projects as reference.</p>
<p>That said, the word &ldquo;interesting&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t nearly enough to distinguish a project that
can be showcased from one that is a jotted down YouTube tutorial.
It is in everyone&rsquo;s benefit to maintain a certain standard and few (lax) rules.</p>
<h1 id="what-constitutes-showcase-worthy-software">What constitutes showcase-worthy software?</h1>
<p>Anything that <strong>serves a clear purpose</strong>.</p>
<p>I have the urge to say &ldquo;anything that <strong>you</strong> create&rdquo;, but this statement leaves a lot of leeway
for lazy/tutorial projects. The rules will still be rather lax.</p>
<p>A project can be showcased if it satisfies the following criteria:</p>
<ul>
<li>Has a proper github <code>README.md</code></li>
<li>Is <strong>not</strong> tutorial material. So anything along these lines is generally discouraged:
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;todo app in react&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;planner app in vue&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;terminal tic-tac-toe with C&rdquo;</li>
<li>and so on&hellip;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Is being actively worked on by it&rsquo;s developer(s).
It is <strong>OK</strong> even if it&rsquo;s in infancy when the project
is first showcased.</li>
<li>Is open to contribution from people.</li>
<li>Is not a lazy fork (Forks that are some-what different from the parent repos are absolutely okay).</li>
</ul>
<p>If you cross out any projects that don&rsquo;t match the above criteria, all that remains is an honest-to-god
project that could use some publicity :)</p>
<h2 id="examples">Examples</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a few examples to show what we mean by &ldquo;showcase-able projects&rdquo;.
Note that not all of them are from the members of cbrtl, since we&rsquo;re just getting started out.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/karnkaul/LittleEngineVk">levk</a>: A 3D Game engine written in C++ and
Vulkan. <strong>Author: <a href="https://github.com/karnkaul">karnage</a></strong></li>
<li><a href="https://aitikgupta.github.io/sociomark/">SocioMark</a>: A social media platform with
plagiarism and attack-proof authenticity checks for user uploaded content.
<strong>Author: <a href="https://github.com/aitikgupta">Aitik Gupta</a></strong></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/srijan-paul/snap">vyse</a>: A fast, dynamically typed and interpreted programming
language. <strong>Author: <a href="https://github.com/srijan-paul">srijan_</a></strong> (<em>cough</em> self-plug)</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/karnkaul/locc">locc</a>: A C++ utility to count lines of code in a project.
<strong>Author: <a href="https://github.com/karnkaul">karnage</a></strong></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rxi/lume">lume</a>: A Lua library for gamedev. <strong>Author: <a href="https://github.com/rxi">rxi</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: Not all future project additions need to be nearly as complex as the projects listed above.</p>
<p>But there is a common running theme with these that you may have caught on to by now.
All these projects are really <em>cool</em> but <em>under-represented</em>.
That right there, is what we&rsquo;re trying to solve.</p>
<p>We want <em>your</em> projects that you build individually or in teams, to get the recognized in a community and to get feedback from
reviewers/users.</p>
<h1 id="getting-your-project-showcased">Getting your project showcased.</h1>
<p>Wooookay, now we get to the point.
You have made something, or at least the skeleton of something that will go on to become
a full fledged project. How do you put your code and product on cbrtl? Heres how.</p>
<ol>
<li>Reach out to use either on the mailing list, or on the discord server</li>
<li>Have the following ready:
<ul>
<li>A GitHub repo with a well set-up <code>README</code></li>
<li>A short/long write-up describing the scope, aim, tech-stack and architecture
of your project. (Need not be serious at all)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Shoot any moderator with the aforementioned and we&rsquo;ll give you:
<ul>
<li>A GitHub repo symlink (<em>symlink?</em>) on the <a href="https://github.com/cbrtl">cbrtl org page</a>.</li>
<li>A community showcase.</li>
<li>A blog post referencing the content from your write-up, describing the project.</li>
<li>Encourage other members to collaborate and contribute.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>A good place to start getting involved can be our <a href="https://discord.gg/3qry3u569v">Discord server</a>.</p>
<h1 id="have-an-idea-want-a-team">Have an idea? Want a team?</h1>
<p>It is not so uncommon for programmers to get an idea but not have enough
time commitment (or knowledge) to drive the idea to fruition. If that&rsquo;s how things end up
for you, then let us know about your ideas and we can see if enough members in the community
are interested to collaborate.</p>
<p>We may be able to help turn your solo idea into a collaborative work environment.
You can choose to have the repo be on the org, or on your GitHub profile.</p>
<h1 id="closing-with-some-general-thoughts-and-other-goals">Closing with some general thoughts and other goals.</h1>
<p>In the future, we also want to create teams for <strong>Hackathons</strong> and <strong>Competitive Programming</strong> events
(I&rsquo;m <strong>not</strong> a fan of the latter personally, but I understand people will have differing opinions).</p>
<p>As mentioned in the previous post, we are looking for some volunteers in content writing, editing, front-end dev,
code reviews and moderation.
If you have any other ideas in general that can help us grow, let us know :)</p>
<p>Reach out to us if you&rsquo;re a programmer and want to join a community of people who
like to create.</p>
<p>What else do I say, we&rsquo;re just getting started out after all.</p>
<p>Adios.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
